<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Blogs on Eric Ekholm</title>
    <link>/blog/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Blogs on Eric Ekholm</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-US</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Fri, 24 Jul 2020 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="/blog/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Intro to {rvest}</title>
      <link>/blog/dss-webscrape/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 24 Jul 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/blog/dss-webscrape/</guid>
      <description>TL;DR – {rvest} is awesome. Before yesterday, I had 0 experience web scraping and very little experience with HTML/CSS in general, and in a couple of hours, I managed to submit a form and scrape the resulting tables. And it would have been even less time if I weren’t a dummy a remembered that NULL is a thing…more on that later.
MotivationYesterday, for work, I needed to get a list of all of the Family Day Homes (FDH) in Virginia to check against another dataset.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Unconsciousness in the Xmen</title>
      <link>/blog/poisson-xmen/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 14 Jul 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/blog/poisson-xmen/</guid>
      <description>A part of me has always wanted to get into comic books. I think it would be a really good fit for me – I’m definitely a nerd. I play video games, I read fantasy novels, I code/do data science for fun. Comic books should be right up my alley. But for whatever reason, I’ve never taken the plunge. Maybe it’s a time commitment thing. Maybe I know I’ll like them too much.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Exploring Emily Oster&#39;s COVID Data</title>
      <link>/blog/emily-oster-covid/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 25 Jun 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/blog/emily-oster-covid/</guid>
      <description>I’m a big fan of Emily Oster. Well, her work; I don’t know her personally, but she seems cool. As someone with a background in academic research, and also as a new parent, I really appreciate the thoroughness, honesty, and approachability of Cribsheet. And I’m glad she summarized all of the academic articles so I didn’t have to look for them. More recently, I’ve been a big fan of her Parent Data newsletter, which I read (on days it comes out) while my daughter Emma is napping in the morning.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Pulling YouTube Transcripts</title>
      <link>/blog/youtube-transcripts/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 15 May 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/blog/youtube-transcripts/</guid>
      <description>I’ve been a fan of the Your Mom’s House Podcast for a long time now, and I thought it would be interesting to do some analysis of their speech patterns. If you follow the show at all, you know that the conversations are…special (you can check here for a visualization I did of their word usage over time if you’re so inclined). Fortunately, it’s possible to get transcripts of YouTube videos.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Writing Window Functions</title>
      <link>/blog/window-func-programming/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 06 May 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/blog/window-func-programming/</guid>
      <description>I was recently working on exploring some time series data for a Kaggle competition and found myself wanting to calculate the rolling average of some sales. I don’t often work with time series data, so I had to look up functions to use to calculate rolling averages (n.b. that if you don’t know what a rolling average is, read here), and I was surprised that dplyr doesn’t have one built in.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>RVA Pets</title>
      <link>/blog/rva-pets/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 23 Apr 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/blog/rva-pets/</guid>
      <description>I recently stumbled across the RVA Open Data Portal and, when browsing through the datasets available, noticed they had one on pet licenses issued by the city. Since I’m a huge dog fan &amp;amp; love our pitty Nala more than most people in my life, I figured I’d splash around in the data a little bit to see what I can learn about pets in RVA. You can get the data here, although note that the most recent data is from April 2019.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Scrantonicity - Part 2</title>
      <link>/blog/office-part2/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 16 Apr 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/blog/office-part2/</guid>
      <description>Would I rather be feared or loved? Easy. Both.A few weeks ago, I did some exploratory analyses of dialogue from The Office. That blog could easily have been a lot longer than it was, and so instead of writing some gigantic post that would have taken 30 minutes+ to read, I decided to separate it out into several different blog posts. And so here’s volume 2.
In this post, I want to try using k-means clustering to identify patterns in who talks to whom in different episodes.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Riddler Express - March 20, 2020</title>
      <link>/blog/riddler-express-mar-20-20/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 31 Mar 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/blog/riddler-express-mar-20-20/</guid>
      <description>One of my personal goals for 2020 is to improve my proficiency doing data-y things – mostly using R, but potentially other software as well. Typically, I’ve been using data from the #TidyTuesday project to practice data visualization and data from Kaggle, personal research projects, and other potentially interesting datasets to work on statistical modeling. I recently discovered The Riddler series – a weekly math/logic puzzle – that seems to be a good medium for brushing up on other skills (e.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Scrantonicity - Part 1</title>
      <link>/blog/office-part1/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 14 Mar 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/blog/office-part1/</guid>
      <description>I Just Want to Lie on the Beach and Eat Hog DogsWho doesn’t love The Office? I went through high school and college following the on-again off-again romance of Jim and Pam, the Icarus-esque ascendancy and fall of Ryan the Temp, and the perpetual cringey-ness of Michael Scott. And aside from that handful of people who fled the room in a cold panic at even the mention of “Scott’s Tots,” I think this was probably true for most of my generation.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Early Childhood in VA Mapping</title>
      <link>/blog/vq-mapping/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 22 Feb 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/blog/vq-mapping/</guid>
      <description>I started working in the Virginia Department of Education’s Office of Early Childhood about 10 months ago, and since then, I’ve learned a ton about the early childhood landscape across the commonwealth – how many different programs there are that provide supports for early childhood, who qualifies for these programs, how publicly-funded programs intersect and interact with private (read: paid for by families) programs, how families learn about and enroll their children in early childhood care and education (ECCE).</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Tidymodels Walkthrough</title>
      <link>/blog/tidymodels-walkthrough/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 26 Jan 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/blog/tidymodels-walkthrough/</guid>
      <description>The point of this post is to explore some of the packages and capabilities of the {tidymodels} universe of packages, including:
rsamplerecipesdialsparsniptuneyardstickTogether, these packages can help streamline the modeling process. The point of this post is not to try to build the best model(s) possible for the given data, and I’m skipping over a bunch of the exploration I would normally do before modeling to get right into the modeling steps.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>maynaRd</title>
      <link>/blog/maynard/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 20 Jan 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/blog/maynard/</guid>
      <description>I think I first discovered Tool in middle school, when I borrowed my dad’s CDs to listen to on the bus ride to school. This was right when Lateralus came out, and I remember listening to “Schism” over and over and over, staring out of the dingy bus window every morning. Ever since then, I’ve been a huge fan – not just of Tool, but also of Maynard James Keenan’s other bands: A Perfect Circle and Puscifer.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>