<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Blogs on Eric Ekholm</title>
    <link>/blog/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Blogs on Eric Ekholm</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-US</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Tue, 31 Mar 2020 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="/blog/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Riddler Express - March 20, 2020</title>
      <link>/blog/riddler-express-mar-20-20/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 31 Mar 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/blog/riddler-express-mar-20-20/</guid>
      <description>One of my personal goals for 2020 is to improve my proficiency doing data-y things – mostly using R, but potentially other software as well. Typically, I’ve been using data from the #TidyTuesday project to practice data visualization and data from Kaggle, personal research projects, and other potentially interesting datasets to work on statistical modeling. I recently discovered The Riddler series – a weekly math/logic puzzle – that seems to be a good medium for brushing up on other skills (e.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Scrantonicity - Part 1</title>
      <link>/blog/office-part1/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 14 Mar 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/blog/office-part1/</guid>
      <description>I Just Want to Lie on the Beach and Eat Hog DogsWho doesn’t love The Office? I went through high school and college following the on-again off-again romance of Jim and Pam, the Icarus-esque ascendancy and fall of Ryan the Temp, and the perpetual cringey-ness of Michael Scott. And aside from that handful of people who fled the room in a cold panic at even the mention of “Scott’s Tots,” I think this was probably true for most of my generation.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Early Childhood in VA Mapping</title>
      <link>/blog/vq-mapping/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 22 Feb 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/blog/vq-mapping/</guid>
      <description>I started working in the Virginia Department of Education’s Office of Early Childhood about 10 months ago, and since then, I’ve learned a ton about the early childhood landscape across the commonwealth – how many different programs there are that provide supports for early childhood, who qualifies for these programs, how publicly-funded programs intersect and interact with private (read: paid for by families) programs, how families learn about and enroll their children in early childhood care and education (ECCE).</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Tidymodels Walkthrough</title>
      <link>/blog/tidymodels-walkthrough/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 26 Jan 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/blog/tidymodels-walkthrough/</guid>
      <description>The point of this post is to explore some of the packages and capabilities of the {tidymodels} universe of packages, including:
rsamplerecipesdialsparsniptuneyardstickTogether, these packages can help streamline the modeling process. The point of this post is not to try to build the best model(s) possible for the given data, and I’m skipping over a bunch of the exploration I would normally do before modeling to get right into the modeling steps.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>maynaRd</title>
      <link>/blog/maynard/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 20 Jan 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/blog/maynard/</guid>
      <description>I think I first discovered Tool in middle school, when I borrowed my dad’s CDs to listen to on the bus ride to school. This was right when Lateralus came out, and I remember listening to “Schism” over and over and over, staring out of the dingy bus window every morning. Ever since then, I’ve been a huge fan – not just of Tool, but also of Maynard James Keenan’s other bands: A Perfect Circle and Puscifer.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>